

WERSITE

https://dreamstate.graphics

EMAIL

kevin@dreamstate.graphics

PHONE

(845) 649-7476 N

REA

New York

SKILLS

Front-end Development

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, TypeScript, React.JS, Angular.JS, Unit Testing, Jest.js

Back-end Development

Node.JS, Express.JS, C#, .NET, PHP, WordPress, AWS, Server-side Rendering, Routing, Authentication Procedures, User Session Management

Graphic Design

UI / UX, Vector Graphics, Raster Graphics, Motion Graphics, Mock-ups Photography, Illustrator, Photoshop, After Effects, XD, Figma

Database Design / Development

SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres, Analytics, Query Optimization, ORM abstractions

API Development / Integrations

REST, SOAP, GraphQL, RPC, Effective Data Sanitization, End-Point Throttling

Project Management

Great communication skills, Converts ideas into technical projects and vice versa, Great client engagement with mock-ups and demos, Gives accurate options, solutions and estimates.

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Kevin Cox

A holistic, ideas-driven developer that uses a diverse skill-set to supply any technical or graphical need. A firm believer in requiring a foundational understanding of web technologies and project ideas to provide a wide array of user-oriented solutions, while remaining framework agnostic. Specializes in scaling the branding and web operations of small to medium sized businesses, but is comfortable in large production environments. Can work with vibes, or APIs.

EDUCATION

BFA Graphic Design
2018-22 | Binghamton University

EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer

Red Barn Technology Group | Binghamton, NY | Jun. 2022 - Jun. 2023

Designed, developed, and managed a team of 5 to serve and maintain 7 on-going clients. Led and developed a middleware server to integrate a new open-source ERP software for their internal departments into web portals. Maintained, supported and repaired previous clients' projects.

Web Developer Intern

FPS Apparel | Chester, NY | Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

Assessed and advised their technology stack for optimization and additions for internal operations. Created graphics and maintained their Shopify storefront. Jump-started a new software integration, Ziflow, for clients to provide feedback on top of their mocked-up apparel designs.

Web-Dev / Graphics Freelancer

Dream State Graphics | New York, NY | Jan. 2021 - Current

My own freelancing company that takes on any graphical or web-based projects. Projects included a menu for a local diner, a website for a pool company to take inquiries, and a teaching application where teachers can create a "teaching map" to overlay a student commenting system.